Sakanoue Gammon sought an Orpheus Armlet and gained a new power.
（モニター・真方ジン）「逆之上ギャモンは
オルペウスの腕輪を求め→
新たな力を得た」。
No way! Gammon put on an Armlet?
（軸川ソウジ）そんな…
ギャモン君が　オルペウスの腕輪を!?
「そして　やつは知った。→
Thus, he found out
未来に
２人の私が存在する事を…」。
that in the future there are two of me.
One of them is Daimon Kaito. The other...
（ジン）
一人は　大門カイト。　もう一人は…。
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）
もう一人は…　誰なんだ？
Who's the other?
（モニター・レイツェル）
「未来は　揺らぎの中にあるわ」。
The future is constantly twisting.
「決めるのは　お前たちだ。
ファイ・ブレインの子供たち」。
That decision is up to you,
children of the Phi Brain.
オルペウスが候補に選んだ者から
カイト君を除くと→
The candidates Orpheus chose beside Kaito are
残るは　ギャモン君　フリーセル君　レイツェル
そして…→
Gammon, Freecell, Raetsel, and Chief Rook.
ルーク管理官。
You requested aid from other countries to observe Amgine and limit my options.
（ジン）「各国に協力を仰いで
アムギーネ共和国を監視し→
私の動きを封じる…。→
その程度の事は
たやすく見える。→
That much is outright obvious.
私に見えないのは　大門カイト
やつだけだ。→
The only thing I can't see is Daimon Kaito alone.
無駄なあがきは　やめ
ファイ・ブレインとして覚醒しろ。→
Stop your pointless struggle, and awaken as a Phi Brain,
ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド」。
Rook Banjo Crossfield.
I'm not the only one challenging Orpheus's test puzzles.
心の声
（大門カイト）オルペウスの
試練のパズルに挑んでいるのは→
今のところ　俺と…。
（フリーセル）ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。→
（井藤ノノハ）
フリーセル君　解いたのね？　パズル。
Freecell, you solved it, right?
まだ続けるの？
ああ。
Can you go on?
Yeah. Someone's gotta catch up to Kaito and exceed him.
誰かが　カイトに追いつき
追い越さないといけないからね。
フリーセル君…。
Freecell...
The more candidates there are the better.
心の声
（フリーセル）候補は　多い方がいい。
And Raetsel... What is she planning?
心の声
そして…　レイツェル！
あいつは　どうするつもりなんだ？
（ジン）試練のパズルを
何度　解放しても→
It doesn't matter how many of my test puzzles you solve,
お前は　ファイ・ブレインに覚醒しない。→
you'll never awaken as a Phi Brain.
逆之上ギャモンの　パズル能力は
急速に高まっているぞ。
Sakanoue Gammon's puzzling skill is growing rapidly.
つまり　お前には必要なのだ。
腕輪の助けが…。
That means you need the help of an Armlet as well.
オルペウス…　約束して。
Orpheus, give me your word
私が　ファイ・ブレインとして覚醒したら
必ずジンを助けるって。
that if I awaken as a Phi Brain, you'll save Jin.
（ジン）そんな事をして
何の意味がある？
What's the point in doing that?
Just do it!
いいから　約束してよ！
Fine.
いいだろう。　私だって
この滅びかけた肉体に→
I don't want to stay in this dying body forever.
いつまでも
とどまっていたくはない。→
I give you my word,
約束しよう。　お前が
ファイ・ブレインとなった暁には→
that the moment you become a Phi Brain, I'll release Makata Jin.
真方ジンを解放すると。
賢者のパズルを解くわ。→
I'll solve a Sage Puzzle and get an Orpheus Armlet.
そして　オルペウスの腕輪を
手に入れてみせる。
（レイツェル）ちょ…　ちょっと　オルペウス？
What? Orpheus!
駄目…　だ…。→
Don't... do it... Raetsel...
レイ…　ツェル…。
ジン！
レイ…　ツェル。
Jin!
Raetsel...
I wanted to see you so much, Jin!
（レイツェル）会いたかった　ジン！
オルペウスの腕輪をつける…　な…。→
Don't... put on... an Orpheus Armlet...
つけては…　いけない。→
You... mustn't...
君の…　パズル能力は高い。→
You're extremely skilled with puzzles already,
so if you put on the Armlet, it might destroy your... brain...
だからこそ…　腕輪と君の能力が→
君自身の脳を
破滅へと導く危険が…　うっ！
（レイツェル）もうやめて。　ジンは
もう十分　戦ったじゃない。
Stop it already. You've fought for long enough.
レイツェル…。
Raetsel...
（レイツェル）私　知ってるのよ。→
I know that ever since you locked Orpheus's mind away along with your memories,
自らの記憶と共に　オルペウスを
封じ込めてきた　あなたが→
you've struggled with him every moment in your body and heart.
その体と　そして　その心の中で→
ずっとずっと
オルペウスと戦い続けてきた事。
（ジン）俺が消える時は
必ず　あいつを道連れに…。
When my final moment comes, I'll be sure to take him along with me.
Don't talk about final moments!
消えるなんて言わないで！
I'll be sure to save you!
絶対に　私が　あなたを助けるから。
駄目だ！　腕輪の事は忘れろ。
Don't! Forget about the Armlet!
レイツェル…　君は　俺にとって…→
Raetsel, for me you're very—
うっ！　くっ…。
ジン!?
Jin!
Jin...
ジン！
（ジン）お前に　やろう。
望みのものを。
You can have what you desire.
あ…。
忘れるな。
Do not forget: Makata Jin doesn't have much time left.
真方ジンの命が
尽きる時は　近い。
（ジン）この迷路は
重力がゆがんだ空間にある。
Gravity isn't consistent in the space of this maze.
Is that the goal?
（レイツェル）あそこが　ゴール…。
（ジン）ルールは　ただ一つ。→
There is only one rule. You can only go down the stairs.
この迷路にある階段は
下りる事のみ許される。→
決して
上ってはいけない。→
You are not allowed to climb any stairs. If you break this rule...
もしも　ルールを破ったら…。
（ジン）
用意は　いいか？　パズルタイム　スタート。
Are you ready?
It's puzzle time!
（レイツェル）あれは…　ジンと私？
Is that Jin and I?
≪乾杯！
Cheers!
（２人）プハー！
おいしいね　ジン。
It tastes great, Jin!
無事にパズルが解けた　お祝いだ。→
This is to celebrate solving that puzzle.
Having some luxury is nice every now and then, isn't it?
たまには　こういう
豪華な食事も　いいだろ？
え～　ジンが　いつも作ってくれる
ご飯も　おいしいよ。
But the food you cook is good enough.
でも　ここは
三つ星レストランなんだぞ。
But this is a three star restaurant.
みつ…　ぼし？
Three... star?
星が３つは
「とっても　おいしい」って意味さ。
Three stars mean that it's very good.
ふ～ん。
じゃあ　ジンの料理は
星１００個だね。
Then your cooking's a hundred stars!
星１００個!?
アハハハ　大げさだな　レイツェルは。→
A hundred stars?!
Oh come on, Raetsel.
でも　ありがとな。
But thanks anyway.
ねえ　もう一度
乾杯しようよ！
ああ。
Hey, let's do another cheers!
Fine.
レイツェルに…。
星１００個のジンに…。
To Raetsel!
To the 100-star Jin!
（２人）乾杯！
Cheers!
心の声
（レイツェル）懐かしいな…。
あのころは　本当に楽しかった。→
This brings back memories.
I had so much fun back then, just being with Jin. Those were the days.
ジンと２人でいるだけで
最高だった。
（ジン）レイツェルは　あんな危険なパズルに
二度と１人で近づいちゃ駄目だぞ。
You mustn't go near such a dangerous puzzle alone ever again. Got it?
But I want to help y—
でも　私は　ジンの手伝いを…。
（ジン）ほら。
Here.
（レイツェル）これは？
What's this?
俺のお守りだ。　これからは
レイツェルに持っていてほしい。→
A protective charm I had.
You should keep it.
俺が　愚者のパズルに挑んでいる間
俺の無事を祈って→
While I'm challenging Fools' Puzzles, please wait for me and pray for my safety.
待っててくれよな。
Soon after that...
心の声
（レイツェル）そのあと
間もなくして　ジンは…。
あ…　ああ…。
（レイツェルの声）行かせては駄目。→
Don't let him go!
ジンを追いかけて！→
Go after him!
ジンを止めるの。　早く！
止めないと　ジンは→
Stop him! Hurry!
If you don't, he's gonna fight Count Pythagoras in the Divine Puzzle!
神のパズルで　ピタゴラス伯爵と
戦ってしまう！
あの時　ジンを止めていれば…。
If only I had stopped him back then...
心の声
（レイツェル）ファイ・ブレインになれば→
If I become a Phi Brain, I can interfere with the past and maybe even save Jin.
過去に介入して　ジンを
助けられるかもしれない。→
そうよ…　全て　なかった事に…。
Yeah! I can just make it all as if it never happened!
心の声
（レイツェル）待っていて　ジン！
Wait for me, Jin!
（ジン）無駄だ　真方ジン。→
It's pointless, Makata Jin.
It doesn't matter how much you struggle, your voice can't reach Raetsel.
どんなに　あがいても
貴様の声は　レイツェルには届かない。
The preparations for the Puzzle of God will be completed soon.
（エニグマ）神のパズルの準備は
間もなく整います。
I see.
そうか。
あの…→
Um... When can I see Lovushka again?
ラヴーシュカとの再会は　いつごろに…？
もう間もなくだ。→
Very soon.
お前も　その腕に女を迎える準備を
進めるがいい。
You should prepare yourself to welcome your woman once again.
ラ…　ラヴーシュカ…。
Lovushka...
心の声
こうしていると
全ては夢なんじゃないかって…→
At times like these, it all almost feels like just a dream.
そんな気がしてくるよ。→
絶望的な未来。→
The devastated future...
That Jin turned into Orpheus...
ジンさんが
オルペウスになってしまった事。→
カイトやフリーセル君が　必死に
試練のパズルを解き続けてる事…。
That Kaito and Freecell keep solving test puzzles...
心の声
ジンさんは　大切な人。
それは分かってる。→
Jin's important to him... I get that.
でも…。
But...
（ジン）パズルとの出会いは
人との出会いなんだよ。→
Encounters with puzzles are encounters with people.
解いてやれ　自由にしてやれ
パズルを…。
Solve them. Free the puzzles.
パズルには罪がない。
それを作った人間に罪があるんだ。
The puzzles did nothing wrong.
It's all the fault of the people who made them.
ジン。　あいつは…　オルペウスは
人間じゃない。　化け物だよ。
Jin, he... Orpheus isn't human. He's a monster.
化け物を倒すのは
勇者の使命さ！
It's the destiny of heroes to defeat monsters!
ジン…。
Jin...
If I could see into Orpheus's mind, I could save Jin...
（ルーク）オルペウスの考えが　僕に見えたら
ジンを救えるのに…。
（ビショップ）今　ご自身が
ファイ・ブレインになったら…→
You just considered becoming a Phi Brain yourself, did you not?
そう　お思いになりましたね？
お前に読まれるとは
管理官失格だな　僕も。
Even you can read my thoughts... I'm such a failure of a chief.
オルペウスの中にいるという
真方ジンの意識は→
Would it be possible to use Makata Jin's consciousness within Orpheus to resolve this situation?
現状を打破する切り札には
なりえないのでしょうか。
We have no proof that Jin is really in Orpheus.
本当に　ジンが　オルペウスの中にいる
という確証は　どこにもない。
I see.
なるほど。　確かに→
Indeed, we only heard that his mind is living within Orpheus from Orpheus himself.
真方ジンの意識が　オルペウスと
共存していると言ったのは→
オルペウス本人のみ。
「ジンに生きていてほしい」。
そう思う　人間としての弱さを→
I want Jin to live.
I think Orpheus is just using this wish, this human weakness, ag—
恐らく　オルペウスは利用して…。
ルーク様…。
Sir Rook?
心の声
（レイツェル）４つとも　上り階段？
これじゃ　先へは進めない。→
All four sets of stairs go up. I can't move on from here.
どうすれば　あそこへ…。
How can I get there?
このパズルを解放して　オルペウスの腕輪を
手に入れなければ…。
I must solve this puzzle and get the Orpheus Armlet.
こっちじゃないかな？
Isn't it this way?
（ルーク）え～　そっちじゃ
行き止まりじゃない？
But that way is a dead end.
心の声
（レイツェル）ジン!?
Jin!
やっぱ違うよ　ルーク。
カイトこそ間違ってるよ。
That can't be, Rook.
You're wrong, Kaito.
I'm sure you need to do it this way.
これは　こうするんだよ　きっと。
心の声
（レイツェル）大門カイトと　ルーク？
何なの　これ…。
Daimon Kaito and Rook?
What's this?
あれっ？　駄目だ。
だから言っただろ。
Ah, it didn't work.
I told you! It must be this wa—
ここは　こうして…。
Or not.
あれれれれ？
ほら　カイトだって違うじゃないか。
See? You're wrong too, Kaito.
何だと!?
（ルーク）ほんとの事でしょ。
What was that?
But you are!
（ジン）２人とも　ナイストライだぞ。
その調子で頑張れ。
Nice try, boys. Keep it up!
Hell right!
I'm gonna solve this puzzle!
Jin... He's watching them with such kind eyes...
心の声
（レイツェル）ジン…　なんて優しい目で
カイトたちを見てるの。
No, I'm gonna solve it!
（ルーク）解くのは僕だよ！
僕だ！
No, me!
（ジン）こらこら　ケンカは駄目だぞ。
Hey! No fighting.
I've got no choice then!
≪もう！
ルークもカイトも　しょうがないな～。
２人が　ケンカしてるなら
レイツェルが解いちゃお～っと。
If you two are gonna fight, I'm gonna solve the puzzle!
え～っと　これが　こうなって…。
You do it like this!
ああ！　すごいじゃない　レイツェル。
頑張れ　レイツェル　その調子。
Wow! You're pretty good, Raetsel!
Good one, Raetsel! Keep it up!
（レイツェル）へへ～ん　私に任せて！
Just leave it to me!
心の声
レイツェルが　俺たちと一緒に…。
Raetsel's there with us?
（ルーク）頑張れ　レイツェル！
Good luck, Raetsel!
心の声
（ルーク）これは…！→
What? Is this one of Orpheus's illusions of the past?
これが　オルペウスが見せるという
過去の幻影…？
あっ　レイツェル　もしかして
ここは　こうなんじゃないか？
Wait, Raetsel, shouldn't it go this way here?
ほんとだ！　すごい　カイト！
You're right! Amazing, Kaito!
チェッ。
へへ～ん。
Hmph.
ん…　分かった！
ここは　こうだよ。
Oh, I got it! You go this way here!
ルークも　すごい　すご～い！
Wow, you're great too, Rook!
レイツェルが　途中まで
解いてくれたからだよ。
I can only do it because you solved half of it.
ルークの言うとおり。
すごいよ　レイツェル！
You're right, Rook! Raetsel's great!
心の声
あいつ　あんなに
かわいく笑うんだ…。
She can be cute and laugh too...
心の声
（ルーク）ファイ・ブレインになったら
過去すら変える事ができる。→
So if I became a Phi Brain, I can change the past—
それを　オルペウスは
僕に証明しようとでも…。→
Is Orpheus trying to prove that to me?
あっ！
いや…　オルペウスの仕業じゃない。
Wait, no! This isn't Orpheus's doing!
（子供たち）できた～！
Did it!
Look, Jin!
（レイツェル）
ジン　見て見て！　解いたよ。
We solved it!
すごいだろ　僕たち。
We're awesome, aren't we?
レイツェルが頑張ったからでしょ。
そうだった…。
It's thanks to Raetsel, isn't it?
Right...
違うよ。
３人で力を合わせたからだよ。
No, it's because the three of us worked together!
レイツェルは優しいな。
You're so kind, Raetsel.
だって　レイツェル
カイトも　ルークも　ジンも→
Because Kaito and Rook and Jin, I love you all lots-lots-lots!
３人とも
大　大　だ～い好きなんだも～ん！
カイト　ルーク　レイツェル。
（子供たち）うん？
Kaito, Rook, Raetsel. Don't forget this day.
（ジン）３人とも
今日という日を忘れるな。→
そして　大切なものは手放すな。→
Don't let go of what's important.
絶対に…　手放すんじゃないぞ。
Don't let go, no matter what.
私も…
私も　あそこに　いたかった。
I... I wanted to be there too, with those three.
あの３人と一緒に
パズルを解いてみたかった…。
I wanted to puzzle together with them.
夢？
A dream? No.
いや…。
What's wrong, Sir Rook?
（ビショップ）
どうなさいました？　ルーク様。
ルーク様…。
作戦を変更する。
Sir Rook?
Change of plans.
心の声
（ルーク）カイト…
君が正しかったみたいだ。→
Kaito, it seems you were right.
僕は　僕のすべき事をする。
それでいいよね？　ジン。
I'll do what I'm meant to do.
That should be fine, right, Jin?
心の声
（レイツェル）先へ進むには→
To move on, I must climb one of these four stairways.
４つある上り階段のうち
どれかを進むしかない。→
そして　それは…。
The right one is...
フッ　当たりね。
Got you.
心の声
（レイツェル）ここは
オルペウスが　つくり出した世界。→
This is a world Orpheus made.
The direction of gravity is different for these stairs.
この階段だけ　重力の向かう方向が
違うんだわ…。
ジン…。
Jin...
（ジン）うっ!?→
すまない…　レイツェル。→
I'm sorry, Raetsel.
俺のせいで
こんな事になってしまって…。
It's my fault that it's come down to this.
いいのよ　ジン。　あれは
あなたが見せてくれたんでしょ？
It's fine, Jin.
You showed me that, didn't you?
ありがとう。　あの幸せな過去が
現実になるのなら→
Thanks.
If that happy past can become reality, that's enough for me.
他には　もう何も要らないわ。
やめろ　レイツェル。
Stop it, Raetsel! You don't have to do that to—
そんな事をしなくても
君は…　うっ!?
Very good.
それでいい。
その腕輪を使い
お前の望みを　かなえるがいい。
Use that Armlet to fulfill your wish.
次は　もっとレベルの高いパズルにして
オルペウス。
Make it an even harder puzzle next time, Orpheus.
心の声
（レイツェル）悲しまないで　ジン。
これでいいの。→
Don't be sad, Jin. It's fine this way.
私は　守るって決めたんだから…。
I've made up my mind to protect you.
Preview
Up? Down? I don't know.